<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Working-papers on Jeffrey B. Arnold</title>
    <link>/working-papers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Working-papers on Jeffrey B. Arnold</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="/working-papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Shrinkage in Dynamic Linear Models: Unifying Smoothing and Structural Break Models</title>
      <link>/working-papers/smoothing-breaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-papers/smoothing-breaks/</guid>
      <description>This develops a method for estimating time varying parameters that unifies change-point and smoothing models. It unifies these approaches by noting that change point models are simply a case of a sparse parameter model in which the sparsity is over the difference rather than the level of the parameters. The method presented in the essay consists of combining dynamic linear models with newly developed Bayesian shrinkage prior distributions. This method has several advantages over existing change point models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil War as a Hidden Markov Model</title>
      <link>/working-papers/civil-war-as-a-hmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-papers/civil-war-as-a-hmm/</guid>
      <description>This paper estimates a model of civil war prevalence with a hidden Markov model (HMM) to account for measurement error in classifying civil wars. Since there exist multiple coding rules for civil war with substantial disagreement, each of these coding rules is treated as a noisy indicator of a latent concept. A HMM is used to classify country-years into latent states of civil war and peace and to model the probability of civil war onset and continuation with these latent states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Markets and the Onset of the American Civil War</title>
      <link>/working-papers/onset-american-civil-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-papers/onset-american-civil-war/</guid>
      <description>I estimate the market implied ex ante probability of the onset of the American Civil War using U.S. government and state bonds. Surprisingly, financial markets were surprised by the Battle of Fort Sumter and the start of the war. Prior to Abraham Lincoln’s election in November 1860, the market assigned almost no probability to a war. Even after the secession of several states, the week before the Battle of Fort Sumter, the market assigned a negligible probability, approximately 5%, to war onset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Rulers</title>
      <link>/working-papers/measuring-rulers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-papers/measuring-rulers/</guid>
      <description>We develop a measure of the historical reputation of leaders&amp;lsquo; using their Wikipedia pages.
 draft presentation, Annual Meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association, Chicago, IL, April 13, 2013.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing the Costly Lottery: Financial Market Reactions to Battlefield Events in the American Civil War</title>
      <link>/working-papers/american-civil-war-financial-market-battlefields/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-papers/american-civil-war-financial-market-battlefields/</guid>
      <description>This paper estimates the effects of major battles in the American Civil War on the price of Union bonds. Bond prices are a function of expected future cash flows, and war results can have a large influence on the the expectation of the timely payment of those cash flows. Thus, bond prices provide a method to assess the effects of war events on the expected war result. This allows for understanding how events within war influenced the expected war result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Producing Death: Estimating the Offense-Defense Balance from the Production Function of Battle Casualties</title>
      <link>/working-papers/producing-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-papers/producing-death/</guid>
      <description>250 years ago wars were fought with muskets. Today they are fought with missiles. Yet most empirical and theoretical literature has treated war as a homogeneous process across time. This paper develops a theoretical and quantitative apparatus to describe a key source of heterogeneity in wars, the technology of combat. The technology of combat is the shape of the function that takes military forces as inputs and produces casualties as its outputs, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>